Some movies stay with you forever... and ever... and ever.
Room 237 is a documentary film directed by Rodney Ascher.
A subjective documentary that explores various theories about hidden
meanings in Stanley Kubrick's classic film The Shining.
Five very different points of view are illuminated through voice
over, film clips, animation and dramatic reenactments.
Self, played by Bill Blakemore.
Self, played by Geoffrey Cocks.
Self, played by Juli Kearns.
Self, played by John Fell Ryan.
Self, played by Jay Weidner.
Room 237 is a 2012 American documentary film directed by Rodney Ascher about interpretations of Stanley Kubrick's
film The Shining (1980) which was adapted from the 1977 novel of the same name by Stephen King.
The documentary includes footage from The Shining and other Kubrick
films, along with discussions by Kubrick enthusiasts.
Room 237 has nine segments, each focusing on a different element within The Shining which "may reveal hidden clues and hint at a bigger thematic
oeuvre." Produced by Tim Kirk, the documentary's title refers to a room in the haunted Overlook Hotel featured in The Shining.
Room 237 was screened in the Directors' Fortnight section at
the 2012 Cannes and Sundance film festivals.
Its distribution rights were acquired by IFC Midnight and was
exhibited theatrically and on VOD on March 29, 2013.
The film explores themes of conspiracy theory, filmmaking, cinema history.